‫Hello, everyone, my name is Artem, I'm ALLETE Automation engineer and signify health and a welcome
‫to my class Cyprus from zero to Hero.
‫I have many years experience of hands on experience in this automation of a different selenium based
‫frameworks.
‫But when I switched to Cyprus, I like it so much and don't want to go back to selenium anymore.
‫It's faster, more reliable and overall easier to use so I can write my tests faster and getting consistent
‫result of the test from Weisler in Cyprus.
‫I have found out that there are not so many well organized video tutorials about how to use this framework
‫and implement its best practices.
‫So I decided to create my own class, how to build lessons in the logical order, starting from the
‫basics and increasing complexity for listen to listen.
‫Also, I understand the value of your time spent on the lessons.
‫So I try to efficiently organize all content for maximum productivity during the education process.
‫And no worries, no prior programming skills required.
‫If this will be your first framework for automating applications and you don't have experience with
‫selecting a Web driver, it's totally fine.
‫In the beginning of the class, we will install the application under the Cyprus framework and we will
‫make needed configuration.
‫In the second module.
‫We will learn the concepts how to find any web elements using Cyprus based on the variety of real life
‫example, how to interact with the different types of web elements such as lists, dropdown swept tables,
‫input fields and buttons, dialog boxes, check boxes, radio buttons they select and so on.
‫And of course, we will learn how to make assertions for third module.
‫We'll be about organizing and reusing our code with the beach object design partner.
‫In the fourth module, we will learn how to work with APIs.
‫And if you don't know what the API is, we will talk about it as well.
‫And the last module will be about advanced topics such as environment configurations, reporting and
‫running tests with docker container.
‫By the end of this class, you will have all needed knowledge and skills to automate pretty much any
‫web application use using Cyprus in I.T., there is always room to grow and you will have a solid foundation
‫to move forward.
‫And if you will have any question, you're in the class.
‫You can always reach me out and I will definitely provide the support ready for this exciting journey
‫during the class and see you in the classroom.