‫Hello, guys, welcome back to my Cyprus automation class from zero to Hero, and in this module, we
‫will talk about the networking in Cyprus.
‫What tools do you have in Cyprus to work with network connections?
‫How can you assert network responses?
‫How can you make network responses and stuff like that?
‫In the first?
‫And the second lesson, we will talk about the basics of the networking, about what is API and how
‫does it work and what is Jason object and how to work with the JSON object.
‫If you are familiar with the definition of APIs or what the JSON is, you can skip this lesson and the
‫next lesson and go straight to the lesson number three.
‫If you are not, stay tuned and we will go through about the basics of the APIs and about the JSON object.
‫So what is API?
‫API is stands for Application Programming Interface, which is widely used in the modern world of the
‫Web applications.
‫Think about API as a certain black box which can do some stuff for you, and if you know how correctly,
‫ask the questions.
‫You can receive the answer or response from this black box boy, the certain result.
‫Let's imagine that this box on the screen is our weather API and we send request to this API.
‫And if the request was correct, we can get response, for example, with the current weather.
‫So what kind of request we can do to this API?
‫According to documentation, let's say we know that this weather API can return their current weather
‫in this city.
‫If we will provide the city name as a request, we will get the current weather as a response with the
‫forecast for the next two days.
‫So usually APIs work with the payloads in JSON format.
‫So in this box, typical example of the simple JSON object.
‫And if we send the request to this API that the city name is New York, we will get the response from
‫this API that the current weather, the current temperature is 70 degrees, humidity is forty five and
‫forecast for tomorrow is seventy five and day after tomorrow is sixty.
‫If we will change the city name, for example, to Chicago and send this request again, the weather
‫API will return this object with exactly the same format, but just with the different options.
‫So this is the basic approach, how API works and the representation of the data over here in this box.
‫This is a typical JSON object and this is how most of the Web application work in nowadays.
‫What kind of API request exist so it can be get request, post, request, put and delete, get request
‫is considered to get the request for the specific data for API.
‫For example, in the previous slide, I showed you how we requested the data from the weather API to
‫get their information about the weather forecast based on the city post and put request type of request
‫created to send data to API to create or update the resource.
‫For example, you're submitting some web form or web application and send it to the server post and
‫put request has very similar functionality and we will not go into that much detail.
‫What's the difference between those for our subject?
‫It doesn't really matter.
‫And the little requests remove specified resource based on the request information, what the typical
‫API request consists of.
‫Each API request should have API, your URL, so this is HTP link to the API and usually it's called
‫as End Point.
‫So this is basically Web address.
‫Where will you send your request?
‫Second is headers, usually you do find their content type or if it is secure API and require authorization,
‫you will see their authorization token as well.
‫Then you provide the type of your request, which we discussed on the previous five, get post put and
‫delete and body.
‫But it is JSON object with the request data sometimes get request may not have bought.
‫It has just query string parameters, but post request always will have some body which we are requesting
‫or sending data to the API.
‫This is the four typical components for the API request.
‫Most of the maundering applications are client server.
‫So Web browser is our client and certain backend server with a bunch of APIs working on the server side
‫and our browser during the interactions sends a bunch of API requests.
‫You cannot even imagine how many of those our browser are sending to the certain backend APIs.
‫And then boyens every minute what Cyperus can do, it can intercept some of those calls and provide
‫the mock response to your web browser.
‫This is a very cool Cyprus feature when you can create your own service and provide the response which
‫you actually need for your test.
‫Sometimes you may have pretty complicated end to end scenarios when you will need to provide certain
‫type of data to be displayed on your Web browser to test the scenarios.
‫And this may save you a lot of time because you have two advantages here.
‫You can simulate complicated scenarios.
‫It's the number one and second.
‫It is very fast because you are not spending time on waiting the response for the real server.
‫You don't spend time on the networking.
‫The response from the Cyprus server comes back instantly because it's located on the same machine you
‫are running tests on and the same time you can specify which API calls.
‫You still want to go through to the real API server and which one you want to mock and the examples
‫of the mocking we will definitely cover in this module.
‫Also in Cyprus, you can make actual API requests to the server without UI on behalf of the browser,
‫you can send the API request, get certain response from the backend server and then use this data for
‫something.
‫So what a cool thing about the Cyprus, that it's not just a framework for UI functional testing, it
‫can be used also for API testing.
‫It's kind of a hybrid approach of testing, if you will.
‫So let's summarize what we learn in this lesson about API.
‫API stands for application programming interface.
‫It's like a black box.
‫You can send request to it and get a certain response.
‫Types of request for the APIs are gatepost food and lette.
‫Typical request has your URL headers request type and body.
‫Cyprus has built in server which can intercept browser API request and provide mock responses and also
‫Cyprus can make API request and process the responses.
‫So that's you guys.
‫See you in the next lesson.