‫Hello, guys, welcome back to my Cyprus automation and less from zero to Hero, and in this module,
‫we will talk about the object design pattern and we will learn how to organize our test to make it nicer,
‫more readable and code more reusable.
‫I think you probably heard about the object model object pattern.
‫This is pretty popular topic, IMO, automation engineers.
‫And in this module, I will show you how to implement this beach object button for the cypress and we
‫will not use any Cucumber's or any other shells.
‫On the top of that, we will just use JavaScript and Cyprus.
‫So let's start with creating a new spec gloss, which we will use to write our test using the page object
‫better.
‫So you file.
‫So we created our new file, let's put.
‫Describe.
‫All right, this is the body of our test, and let's go to our first tests, bags, and as you remember,
‫for each of our tests, we use this visit site visit in each test.
‫This is kind of not nice to copy paste the code always when you see the copy paste over the code.
‫Remember that if you copy paste in any code more than two times, then there is definitely place to
‫refactoring because we are using site visit in each and every test.
‫We want to create some before each hook to repeat site visit for us every time so we will not copy paste
‫this thing again and again.
‫So before each.
‫So before every test, this hook will open application for us and then let's right first test and for
‫the beginning, let's ride the test to organize our menu.
‫So as you see, our application has the menu and we you can navigate different pages of our application.
‫So the very first thing we want to organize is the navigation part of our app.
‫And let's name this test as the refined navigation across the pages.
‫So let's go back to our previous test, and as you see, for each of every test we copy pasted, the
‫things like site contains forms, layout in the next test, we did the same thing.
‫Site contains Klick, contains the picture, click and so on.
‫And this is something we want probably to reuse, but not copy paste.
‫So let's create just a page object which will be responsible for the navigation in this menu and we
‫will reuse these functions later on.
‫So how to do that?
‫Let's go to our support folder.
‫In the Cypress structure.
‫We will create a new folder and name it page.
‫Page objects, and I remind you in the file structure of the files picture folder are created for the
‫fixtures and we will talk about it later.
‫Integration is for the test plugins.
‫It's for the plug ins in support folder is for everything else, for all code, which you will need
‫to run your test.
‫So we will keep our page objects under this support folder in inside of our objects.
‫We will create new file and we will call it.
‫Navigation page that.
‫This is a new file and let's create a new class inside of this object.
‫And we will need to create a new instance of this class and assign it to the object.
‫So we created a new object of our navigation page, and now let's create a method which will be responsible
‫for navigation, layout, forms, layout.
‫This was the first page we used for our test.
‫So this sign contains form cycling.
‫This is our code.
‫Go back to our objects and let's name it.
‫Form Layout's Beach.
‫And just copy this code over here.
‫So what else do do we have?
‫And we have former state baker.
‫Let's copy this as well.
‫And this is the bigger picture.
‫All right, we created two methods, each of them responsible for navigation for each of the page.
‫Now let's go to our test and call our object.
‫On navigation page for layout page, I don't really like how we name it, let's remain like this,
‫navigate to and we replace this.
‫Navigate to.
‫OK, this sounds nice or navigate to forms, layout, page and navigate to the bigger page.
‫OK, let's try.
‫How does it work?
‫OK, look what happened.
‫So we were able successfully to navigate to the forms layouts, but when we wanted to click on that
‫picture, that didn't work and why?
‫Because our forms menu was collapsed.
‫Why did that happen?
‫Just over here, when we click on the form menu, it's either open the menu form or collapse the menu
‫menu over here.
‫And we will go to our methods responsible for navigation, to the forums, layouts or they peaker.
‫We see that we first click on the forums and in this example we click on the forums as well, but we
‫actually don't want that.
‫So now we need to add some additional logic which will verify if the menu is open or not and if it is
‫opened, we want to click on the menu item or if it's not, we want to click on the header for this
‫menu item.
‫In our example, it is for us.
‫Let's go and inspect element and we see what we need to do for it.
‫So this is our form.
‫And as we see, we have this small Chevron, which is change his direction.
‫Let's inspect it.
‫And Chevron left.
‫And when we click.
‫On the button, inspect the position is Chevron, right?
‫So we probably what we want to do is to grab the value of this name attribute.
‫And if this attribute is left, it means that menu is closed.
‫We want to click on this menu, otherwise we just won't escape this.
‫So let's write this code right now.
‫And this Chevron is located inside.
‫This is a form name, and we see that this menu is a sibling for that and the icon.
‫So we have an icon one and be icon two.
‫And the forms name is located inside of this eye contact.
‫So in order to access the second the icon, we have to go in one level up to the anchor tag and then
‫select these CHIBBARO and find this out.
‫So let's do this.
‫So we want to find a.
‫So we got the menu and now we will need to find these Chevron left and this is located Underclass Expand
‫State.
‫So these glasses menu icon, this is expen state.
‫So we can use this as a unique identifier and we will need this second G over here.
‫So what we need is find it to find this.
‫Then we need to find first G and second G, then we want to invoke.
‫Attribute is.
‫The name.
‫Attribute the name.
‫Let's go upstairs, then
‫attribute and then we want to write something if our attribute.
‫Includes left, that means our menu is collapsing.
‫We want Cy.
‫Rap menu and click, otherwise, we just skip the if statement and we'll go straight over here.
‫So let's check if this thing will work.
‫Now let's copy this thing.
‫We based it over here.
‫And let's run our test to see if our logic is working.
‫All right, perfect.
‫So, as you see, we were able to select form layout first and then they'd be confirmed.
‫So our code was able to understand if the menu collapsed or not.
‫And if it is not, then we just skip the clicking on the header of the form and select the menu item.
‫Now, let's make small refactoring because we don't want to make this copy paste.
‫Let's extract this method to the reuseable function.
‫So what we did is I extracted this checker for the group is collapse or not do a reusable function named
‫and select group menu item, and I assign the parameter group name, which I use over here inside contains
‫group name.
‫And then I just call our reusable function and provide the group name over here so I can use this function
‫now for any group name inside of our test.
‫So let's run that test and see if it is working.
‫Yes, it is working.
‫Sounds good, and all we have to do right now is just to copy the rest of the methods which we used
‫for navigation.
‫And and we will be able to complete our first object navigation page.
‫All right, I think we're done organizing this, so we created five methods to navigate across different
‫pages is tooltip page, smart table page Towcester Picker and forms layout.
‫Now, let's go back to our test with page objects and let's just navigate to these pages, OK?
‫Navigate to date picture forms, layout, smart table page.
‫And now you see how it is it comfortable to find where we want to navigate Towcester page, tooltip
‫tooltip page and navigate to what was left Towcester page.
‫OK, and let's run this test and we'll check our navigation.
‫All right, perfect.
‫Our navigation across the pages works just fine, and let's quickly summarize what we did in this lesson.
‫So in this lesson we used before each vote for the first time, we put there our side that visit to
‫open our application.
‫And this code will be executed for every test in these described blocks.
‫So in this test class and we created our first page object, which is navigation page object, and put
‫there a few methods in each of the methods responsible for navigation for certain page.
‫And we created one reusable function, which we are using only for these methods.
‫And this function is responsible to determine the state of the main menu.
‫Is it opened or collapsed?
‫So our navigation across the pages will work just fine.
‫And we created a very simple first test which will verify that we can successfully navigate across our
‫pages and we are using page objects.
‫Better to do that.
‫It was the part one.
‫In the second part, we will run more test using page objects.