‫Hello, guys.
‫Welcome back to the class.
‫Cyprus from zero to hero.
‫And in this lesson we will clone and run test application that we're going to use for this class.
‫So the first thing, let's create a new folder on our computer where we will keep our code.
‫Just for this demo.
‫I'm going to create a new folder on the desktop, but you can create it anywhere on your computer where
‫you normally keep your documents or keep your code.
‫If you already have folder on your computer where you keep the source code for other applications,
‫you can use that folder just to keep everything organized.
‫So I create a new folder and let's name it, let's say git repo.
‫Now we need to open this folder in the terminal If you are on my computer.
‫One way of doing this is just right click of the mouse services and new terminal at this folder and
‫the terminal is open.
‫Another option you can go to Spotlight search.
‫Find your terminal.
‫Open the terminal and then simply navigate to this folder.
‫CD.
‫Desktop git repo.
‫And that's it.
‫So as you can see, we are right now inside of this folder, if you are on Windows computer, you do
‫pretty much the same.
‫You will need to find a command prompt terminal on your windows computer.
‫You just go to the start menu search bar and type there command prompt.
‫Then you do pretty much the same thing using the commands CD space and providing the path to the folder
‫where it is located.
‫You need to open this folder in the terminal.
‫So that's the step one.
‫Step number two, we open the browser and go to the GitHub.
‫On the GitHub on the search bar we are searching for in g x Cyprus test.
‫And the very first repository is the one that we are looking for.
‫Bonder Artem Inks Cyprus Test.
‫This is our test project.
‫Also on Udemy, you can find a link to this repository attached to this lesson.
‫Just click on the resources and here is the link GitHub repository.
‫Click on that and you will be navigated to GitHub.
‫So here we need to click on the code button.
‫And then copy this URL.
‫Just simply click on this icon and the entire URL will be copied.
‫Then we go in back to our terminal and type in the command git space, clone space, and we paste the
‫URL that we copied from the GitHub and click enter.
‫That's it.
‫The project is closed to this folder, and now we just need to open Visual Studio code and open the
‫folder that we just copied.
‫This is Visual Studio code, Open file, open folder, and I'm going to the desktop desktop git repo
‫in Cyprus test and make sure that you pick the root of this folder in Cyprus test and click open.
‫Here we go.
‫Application is open.
‫We can see the folder structure on the left.
‫Now the next step we need to install all the dependencies required for this application to actually
‫run it on our computer.
‫We need to open a new terminal, click on the terminal, new terminal and inside of the open terminal.
‫Need to run command and PM space install space dash, dash force and click enter.
‫So now node package manager is done loaded all required dependencies to run this application.
‫So not package manager looking into this package that JSON file and from this dependency section in
‫the loading, all the required packages.
‫We used a dash dash force flag because sometimes on your system you may have some conflicts or warnings
‫because of the conflict with some of the packages that already installed in your computer.
‫In order to avoid that, we just want to bypass this.
‫Bypassing a false flag installation process may take a few minutes, so you just need to patiently wait
‫until it will be completed so it can take like several minutes.
‫All right.
‫An installation is completed at the end of the installation.
‫You may see a window, something like that.
‫That new major version is available.
‫Also, you will see the message like that that some vulnerabilities are found, but just ignore this
‫message.
‫It's related to some of the packages are just not up to date.
‫And because this application is used in Angular eight, some of the packages simply cannot be updated
‫to the higher version.
‫And that's why NPM just showing these kind of warnings.
‫But this is okay for us.
‫All we need is just to run this application on the local host and that's it.
‫The next step to run this application is execute command in PM, start and click enter.
‫And we can see application is building and compiling.
‫All right.
‫And we see a message compiled successfully.
‫This is what we are looking for.
‫And also open your browser on local host 4200.
‫And this is what we need to do.
‫Going back to the Chrome browser, opening a new tab and type in local host 4200.
‫And click enter.
‫Here we go.
‫This is our test application.
‫It's successfully running.
‫It has a different pages.
‫As you can see, we will use for this class like forms, layout, date picker to practice different
‫types of UI elements and how to interact with those types of web elements using Cyprus.
‫All right.
‫So the next step will be to install Cyprus and we will do it in the next lesson.