‫Hello, guys, welcome to my Cyprus automation, plus from zero to Hero, and before we start all automation
‫process and learn how to automate Web application with a Cyprus, first of all, I would like to clarify
‫the terminology which we will use to automate any Web application.
‫You should clearly understand how to locate any Web element on the Web page.
‫And in order to do that, you should know what the DOM is and how to navigate against the dump.
‫So if we make it right, click and inspect element.
‫This is Chrome developer tools of our application on our test and you will see the HTML structure over
‫here.
‫So this is our DOM and you should be very, very confident in how to find Web elements over here.
‫So we will discuss right now the DOM or HTML structure consists of.
‫So you will be very clear how to navigate in HTML and finally cater for any element in HTML.
‫And I would like to talk about it on this example of a simple HTML code for input email field.
‫So let's analyze what it consists of.
‫One of the biggest problem which I have noticed for the automation engineers is the find web elements.
‫And this problem come out of the not clear understanding of what is the naming of each HTML field and
‫each HTML value.
‫And that creates a confusion how to create the correct locators in any automation tool like selenium
‫or especially Cyprus.
‫I would like to clarify that for you.
‫So let's start with HTML.
‫So HTML structure has a HTML tags and these tags called HTML tag name.
‫Usually HTML tags come in pairs with open enclosing deck for example, is deep is open text and D with
‫a forward slash is a closed deck.
‫And this is the input html tag which do not have close.
‫InTech is just have this angle brace which is close in this tack.
‫Inside of the HTML tag are HTML attributes which are in Chrome browser highlighted in red and they called
‫HTML attribute names in HTML attributes has value and they are usually highlighted in blue and sometimes
‫HTML attributes can have values and sometimes they are not.
‫And for example, this HTML attribute name placeholder has a value email or type attribute, has a value
‫email as well.
‫But and be input h html attribute do not have value, but it is attribute as well.
‫Also important thing to note that ID and the class are also HTML attribute names, IDs and classes has
‫a special role in HTML structure because ID is a unique identifier of the web element and class is defined
‫the stylesheet, but it is also attribute names and we will talk about the special roles of ID and classes
‫later.
‫Also, a class name has a values and important to understand that these long class, for example, is
‫not one value.
‫This class has three different values.
‫Glossolalia number one, plus value number two and number three in full.
‫Waithe size medium in Chaib rectangle are three different class values and they are separated by this
‫space.
‫This is also important to know because you can use each of these class name, size, medium or shape
‫rectangle or as a separate locator by class name.
‫Next thing, let's talk about another example of HTML.
‫This is the code for Table, which has a table book body.
‫We have a three table rows one, two, three and four.
‫The first table row.
‫We have three columns as table down, one, two, three, four.
‫And let's talk about it as well as we talk before, each HTML tags usually has open index and close
‫index.
‫In this particular example for table column TD Tag has the closing tag at the end for the table or in
‫table body.
‫They are located in the bottom just because they are opened over here.
‫The values.
‫Between angle braces, in this example, one point eight m.b deer or five.
‫This is the regular text value.
‫So everything what you see on the Web page as a text usually located in between the angle braces.
‫Why?
‫I say usually because not always.
‫Sometimes this text can be hidden in the properties of the browser and we will talk about this later
‫and how to work with the properties and how to get the values and assertive values from the properties.
‫But in most of the cases, all the text you see on the webpage is located in between the angle basis
‫of HTML tags.
‫The small three dots means that there is some nested content inside.
‫And also you can understand by these small icon one, the small arrow turned right.
‫It means that some content is inside of this column.
‫And if you will click in the inspector in the chrome dev tools on this small icon, it will open for
‫you this content.
‫Also, let's talk about the relations between the Web elements.
‫Let's use this table roll with the first table row of our table as our key element, all elements located
‫above our key element, our parent elements.
‫So table body HTML tag is a parent element for table roll and all other elements which will be above
‫the table body and up will be parent elements.
‫All elements which are located inside of the table role are child elements in relation to table row
‫elements and everything.
‫What is inside of table role?
‫All elements which will go deep into the tree is considered a child elements.
‫Sibling elements are elements which are located in the same level of the structure, for example, these
‫table roles for roles, if you draw the straight vertical line, you will see that they're aligned and
‫they are siblings to each other.
‫We have four columns, table downs, which are siblings, and we have three table roles which are also
‫siblings to each others.
‫So this relation of Web elements to each other, you should really clear, understand and let's make
‫a quick summary of what we just discussed in this lesson.
‫HTML contains of HTML tags, HTML attributes and attribute values.
‫Class and Idy are also attribute names, despite they have a special role in the structure.
‫Glass attributes can have a several values in each value is separated by the space HTML tags usually
‫come in pairs of open and enclosed deck close.
‫Intec has the same name and forward slash value in between angle brackets is a plaintext elements above
‫the key web element are parent elements.
‫Elements inside of the key web element are child elements and elements placed at the same level.
‫Side by side are sibling elements to each other.
‫So this is pretty much it.
‫I hope it was useful and we will use all this information in all this knowledge in our next lesson,
‫where will we discuss how to build the locators and how to find the locators in the cypress?
‫So see you in the next lesson.