‫Hello guys.
‫Welcome back to JavaScript Fundamentals Module, and in this lesson we will talk about relational and
‫equality operators.
‫So let's start with the relational one,
‫Relational or comparison
‫for operators.
‫This is also how they call comparison.
‫Let me list them first and I will show you examples.
‫One by one.
‫The first operator called more than
‫this one called Less than.
‫This one called more than
‫more than equal and
‫less than equal.
‫And now let me create a variable colored result.
‫And let's create a first relational or first comparison.
‫So let's say I want to say that ten is more than five.
‫Let's use first operator more than So with the relational operators, we comparing what is on the left
‫with what is on the right.
‫So this particular operator is making comparison.
‫If the value on the left more than value on the right and let's print the result console dot log we
‫print result in the console and execute
‫run it.
‫And what we see, we see the result as true.
‫So the result of relational operators, this is also logical operator will be always a boolean, so
‫it will going to return true or false by confirming us if the ten more than five or not.
‫And if for example I will put four is four more than five and run this one more time, we see the result.
‫All right.
‫This is false because definitely four is not more than five.
‫Four is less than five.
‫That's why it is false.
‫But if I will change my operator to this one, which is called less than in this example we compared
‫is for less than five.
‫And if we run this expression and this time it shows.
‫Yes, of course it is true because four is less than five.
‫Moving on.
‫So let's say if I would put is five less than five?
‫What we have the result is false and or if I put is five more than five run it again and false because
‫of course five is not more than five or not less than five.
‫Five is equal to five and in this example are useful operators like more than equal or less than equal.
‫So we're going to use expression like is five more than equal five.
‫And if I run this one more time, would we see yes, true.
‫So five is not more than five, but five is equal five.
‫So that's why the result of this overall comparison expression will be true if we all put six here and
‫we'll compare is six more than equal five and if we run it?
‫Yes, of course it's true, because six is more than five.
‫But if I put four and execute this one more time, what do I see?
‫I see false because four is less than five.
‫And of course four is not equal to five.
‫And that's why this expression is evaluated in false.
‫And the same way would be to work with less than if I will replace this one to this sign, which is
‫less than.
‫And then we'll run it and we'll see what we have.
‫True, because four is less than five.
‫If I will put five, it's going to be true again, because five is equal to five.
‫And if I will put six, we will have false because six is more than five.
‫That's why it is false.
‫So these comparison operators are used to drive your logic of the application flow.
‫So based on the data that you have, you want to execute this piece of code or that piece of code,
‫and you can derive this logic based on the comparison, based on the different condition, the different
‫branch of the code can be executed and how to manage this logic.
‫We're definitely going to talk about in the next lesson.
‫And let's also talk about equality operators
‫and for the convenience, let me create a new variable.
‫Let me call it just X and x is equal to one and now I print to the console two expressions right inside
‫of the console.
‫So I put X is equal to one and I put the second expression sorry console log console.log and I will
‫put second expression console dot log and x is equal equal equal to one and run this code.
‫Let's see what happened.
‫I'm going to command this.
‫So run this and execute and let's see what we have the first expression evaluated as true.
‫The second one is in false.
‫But what's the difference?
‫This one is true.
‫This one is false.
‫But both are comparing, Hey, X is equal to one and this one x is equal to one.
‫And we know that x is equal to one because we assigned one to our variable.
‫The difference is this one.
‫If we use double equal, we comparing the value on the left to the value on the right, and it's called
‫a loose comparison.
‫We do not compare the data type of the value, we just comparing the value itself.
‫This is one and this is one and they are the same.
‫So that's why it is true.
‫But when we use a triple equal sign, this is a strict comparison.
‫Strict comparison means that we are not only checking the value, but we also checking the data type
‫of the value.
‫In this example, one is a number, but in this example, one is a string, because it is in the single
‫quote.
‫So this expression will be evaluated as false because one as a number is not equal, as one as a string.
‫That's why it's false.
‫But if we will change it to this one equals to one and run it, and now everything works fine.
‫So this evaluation is evaluated in.
‫True.
‫So this is what the difference you need to know.
‫Double equal sign means it's a loose comparison.
‫If value on the left is equal to the value on the right without validation of the data type.
‫And the triple equals is more strict comparison when the value on the left should be equal by the value
‫to the right and the data type should be the same as the value on the left.
‫All right.
‫So let's quickly summarize what we learned in this lesson.
‫So relational or comparison operators are four types, more than less than more than equal and less
‫than equal.
‫The result of the relational and comparison operators will be always boolean, so it will return you
‫true or false when you use equality operators, there are two types.
‫Double equals is the loose comparison.
‫When we just comparing the value and the triple equals when we validating value and the data type and
‫the return result also will be a boolean.
‫All right.
‫Thank you, guys, and see you in the next lesson.